Koopman family papers
Connecticut Historical Society
- V. Other Family Members and Associates
  - Fox, Gerson (1811-1880) – "State’s Movers & Shakers" from The Hartford Courant, March 30, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Fox, Isaac (1858-1939) – Personal Tax, November 1, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - [Fox, Jacob L?] – Menu from The Palatine, January 1, 1902; [2 copies] (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Fox, Jacob L. (1856-1936) – Newspaper Clippings, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Fox, Leopold (1848-1900) – Correspondence, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Fox, Lewis (1904-1976) – Correspondence, Last Will & Testament, Estate Auction, 1940-1977 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Fox, Lewis (1904-1976) – Newspaper Clippings, 1976-77, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Estate, April 15, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Household Expenses, 1912-1928, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Records of Hospital Stay, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Eyeglasses Prescription, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Hartford Woman’s Club Membership, 1926-27 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Newspaper Clippings she saved, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Fox, Theresa Stern (1865-1932) – Newspaper Clippings, Death Notice (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Koopman, Beatrice (b. 1954) – Newspaper Clippings, Foot Guard Dog Show, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Koopman, George A. (1944-1989) – INSGROUP Inc., October 10, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Koopman, George A. (1944-1989) – Pomfret School, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Koopman, George A. (1944-1989) – Newspaper Clippings, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Koopman, Rena A. (1886-1947) – Correspondence, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Koopman, Richard, Jr. (b. 1953) – William H. Hall High School, Graduation Exercises, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Koopman, Richard, Jr. (b. 1953) – Hartford Jewish Community Center membership, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Marks, Morris F. (1863-1938) – Last Will & Testament (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Samuels, Fan Fox Auerbach (1896-1981) – Bristol Nurseries Inc., 1933 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Schiro, Dorothy Auerbach (1919-1998) – United Way Community Service Award, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Schiro, Dorothy Auerbach (1919-1998) – Foundations & Associations – American School for the Deaf, 1944-1964 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Schiro, Dorothy Auerbach (1919-1998) – Foundations & Associations – Connecticut Institute for the Blind (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Schiro, Dorothy Auerbach (1919-1998) – Foundations & Associations – University of Hartford, 1958-1982 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Schiro, Robert (b. 1950) – Correspondence, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Stern, Moses (1863-1929) – Newspaper Clippings, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Woodhouse, Chase Going (1890-1984) – Correspondence and Dedication of ‘The Grist Mill,’, 1953, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Unattributed – Assorted Legal Documents, 1896-1921 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Unattributed – Family Reminiscences at Christmas, 1991, 1992, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Unattributed – Ephemera (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Unattributed – Assorted Newspaper Clippings, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Unattributed – Genealogy (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Unattributed – Genealogical Notes (Box 8, Folder 68)
- I. Administration
  - Correspondence, 1928-1953, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Account Book, 1892-1919 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Account Book, 1892-1925 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - G. Fox & Co., Inc. Record Book, 1920-1956 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Folder 27. Loose Items Removed from G. Fox & Co., Inc. Record Book, 1920-1956 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Financial, 1913-1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Beatrice Fox Auerbach, Notebook of Statistics, 1949-1966 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Legal – Hiring Contracts, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Legal – Dissolution Notice, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Legal – Articles of Copartnership, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Legal – Contract Agreement, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Directors Meeting, January 27, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Board Meeting, February 27, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of Meeting at 1040 Prospect Ave, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Brown Thomson Inc., By-Laws & Meeting Minutes, 1962-1965 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Policy – "Profitless Departments,", February 4, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Policy – "Program Meeting with the Top Group,", 1932 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Policy – "Material Relating to Program for Managerial and Departmental Meetings, Season 1933 and 1934,", 1933-1934 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Policy – "Sixty Second Selling and Raising the Unit Sale,", June 27, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Policy – "Objective for Department Managers of G. Fox and Company, August 1, 1938 to February 1, 1939,", 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Policy – "Aged Rules,", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Policy – "A Creed,", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Policy – Customer Service Exercise, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Policy – "We Do Our Part,", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Policy – Brown Thomson Inc. – "Management Personnel and its Ambitions and Duties," (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Awards & Honors, 1949, 1953, 1965; for 1965 award; see OVERSIZE #35 in Box 12 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Gifts from Employees – Information about Bronze plaque of Moses Fox, November 16, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Gifts from Employees– "Beatrice Fox Auerbach", November 7, 1942; see OVERSIZE #13 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Gifts from Employees – Happy Birthday certificate, July 7, 1947; see OVERSIZE #14 in Box 12 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Gifts from Employees – "A Tribute on the Occasion of her Birthday,", July 7, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Gifts from Employees – "A Volume of Good Wishes, Christmas 1966" (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Gifts from Employees – Certificate of appreciation from the Basement Division, see OVERSIZE #14 in Box 12 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Gifts from Employees – "Once Upon a Time…", see OVERSIZE #16 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Memorandums & Notes, 1969, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Building – Jeter Cook & Jepson Architects, Inc., n.d. (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - History – "Significance of G. Fox and Company’s Centennial Year and the Romance of Merchandise", [1947] (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - History – "A History of G. Fox and Company as an Urban Institution,", 1982 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - History – "G. Fox: Grand Emporium of the Twentieth Century,", 1991 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - History – "G. Fox,", [2002] (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - History – "History of G. Fox & Co, Inc.,", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - History – G. Fox history, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - History – "Main Street, Hartford, About the Time of the Civil War" (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - CD #1 [see Audio Materials List on page 24 for description], in Box 11: Audio-Visual Materials, Folder 3 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - CD #2 [see Audio Materials List on page 24 for description], in Box 11: Audio-Visual Materials, Folder 4 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - CD #3 [see Audio Materials List on page 24 for description], in Box 11: Audio-Visual Materials, Folder 5 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - CD #4 [see Audio Materials List on page 24 for description], in Box 11: Audio-Visual Materials, Folder 6 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - CD #5 [see Audio Materials List on page 24 for description], in Box 11: Audio-Visual Materials, Folder 7 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Events (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Merchandise Information (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - "A Study of Consumers in Hartford, West Hartford, East Hartford, Windsor, and Wethersfield,", [1933] (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Ephemera (Box 9, Folder 46)
- II. Publications
  - Store Map, [ca. 1940] (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Telephone Directories (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Advertisements (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Connecticut Room Menu, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Catalogue of the Connecticut Room Murals (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Highways and Byways of Connecticut, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Highways and Byways of Connecticut – with inscription from Beatrice Fox Auerbach to her granddaughter, Rena Koopman (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Highways and Byways of Connecticut, unbound edition, 1947; see OVERSIZE #17 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - This is Connecticut Living, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Tales of Centinel Hill, 1947; [hardcover]; see OVERSIZE #18 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Tales of Centinel Hill, 1947; [softcover in envelope]; see OVERSIZE #19 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - A Century in Connecticut, 1947; see OVERSIZE #20 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Tales of Centinel Hill, 1955; [reprint from original]; see OVERSIZE #21 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Williamsburg Reproductions: Interior Designs for Today’s Living, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Williamsburg Reproductions: Interior Designs for Today’s Living, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - 1984 Stamp News [from G. Fox & Co. Stamp & Coin Dept.] (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - G. Fox & Co.’s Popular Music, n.d.; see OVERSIZE #22 in Box 12 (Box 9, Folder 63)
- III. Staff
  - A. Personnel
    - Correspondence from Beatrice Fox Auerbach, 1938, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Departments (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Employee Job Descriptions (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Employee Benefits (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Employee Recruitment Brochures (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Employee Training – "Special Training for Mr. Richard Koopman,", 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Employee Training – Cash Register Manual (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Employee Training Manual (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Employee Training Materials (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Employee Newsletters, 1933-1966 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Employee Newsletters, 1967-1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - [Leo Herzfeld?] – Script of "Once upon upon upon a time or every cloud must have a silver lining" (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Freda Pomerantz – "Mrs. David Pomerantz Entertains Foxonians" (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - B. Moses Fox Club
    - Member List, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Member List, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Member List, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Invitation, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Dinner Programs, 1939-1943 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Dinner Programs, 1946-1948 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Dinner Programs, 1952, 1955, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Dinner Programs, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Dinner Program, 1969 [with donation letters] (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Dinner Programs, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Honorary Membership to Judge Solomon Elsner, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Songs for Dinner…, February 4, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Scrapbook of Georgette Koopman, Januery 29, 1944; [empty] (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Scrapbook of W.O. [Warrant Officer] Richard Koopman, January 29, 1944; [empty] (Box 10, Folder 27)
- IV. Newspaper Clippings
  - Advertisements, 1886-1986; for 1985 ad; see OVERSIZE #36 in Box 12 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Art Exhibits, 1949-1966 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Brown-Thomson Merger, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Fire & Rebuilding, 1917-1918, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - G. Fox/May Co. Merger, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - G. Fox’s Salute to Women’s Organizations, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Incorporation, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - May Co., 1967-1974 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Moses Fox Club, 1939-1973 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - "A Page from History: March 30, 1847" in Hartford Courant, 36527 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Programs, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Red Cross Unit, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Store Anniversaries, 1937-1957 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Store Closing, September 12, 1992 - April 15, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Store Closing & Plans for G. Fox Building, 1992-2002 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Store Expansion & Restoration, 1937-1984 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - "Two Great Hartford Newspapers Tell the Inside Story of G. Fox & Co." (Box 10, Folder 44)
- V. Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook, April 11, 1931 - December 28, 1941 (Volume 1)
    see OVERSIZE #23
  - Scrapbook, September 1, 1937 - January 31, 1948; see OVERSIZE #24 (Volume 2)
  - Scrapbook, January 13, 1949 - September 27, 1954; see OVERSIZE #25 (Volume 3)
  - Scrapbook, January 13, 1949 - September 27, 1954; see OVERSIZE #26 (Volume 4)
  - Scrapbook, September 1954 - February 22, 1964; see OVERSIZE #27 (Volume 5)
  - Scrapbook, September 1954 - February 26, 1964; see OVERSIZE #28 (Volume 6)
  - Scrapbook, February 22, 1964 - January 29, 1967; see OVERSIZE #29 (Volume 7)
  - Scrapbook, April 20, 1964 - January 29, 1967; see OVERSIZE #30 (Volume 8)
  - "Merger of G. Fox & Co. and The May Co., October 27, 1965 - December 24, 1965"; [has loose clippings inside front cover]; see OVERSIZE #31 (Volume 9)
  - "Merger of G. Fox & Co. and The May Co., October 27, 1965 - December 24, 1965;", see OVERSIZE #32 (Volume 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1967-1968; see OVERSIZE #33 (Volume 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1967-1968; see OVERSIZE #34 (Volume 12)